Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we've got a very interesting lesson for you all about building your vocabulary.
今天我们为大家准备了一节非常有趣的课，关于如何扩充词汇量。
So we're trying to describe personalities.
我们要尝试描述性格。
You're going to learn tons of new words.
你会学到很多新词。
Exactly.
没错。
And as you said, we're going to describe people's personalities.
就像你说的，我们要描述人的性格。
So not their physical attributes.
而不是他们的外貌特征。
We're going to concentrate on how they are personality wise and stuff like that.
我们会专注于他们的性格特点之类的。
Their character.
他们的品性。
That's right.
对。
So let's take a listen to today's dialogue for the first time and we'll be back in a
那我们先听一遍今天的对话，
moment to talk about some of these great words.
稍后再回来讨论这些精彩的词汇。
Okay, class, settle down.
好了，同学们，安静下来。
I have the results of your individual personality tests.
我拿到了你们个人性格测试的结果。
I'm going to hand them out and if you'd like, you can read them out loud to the rest of
我会发下去，如果你们愿意，可以大声读给全班同学听。
the class.
I'll read mine.
我来读我的。
Okay, go ahead.
好的，请吧。
It says here that I am adventurous, outgoing and easygoing.
上面说我爱冒险、外向、随和。
It says that I'm a little superstitious and occasionally naive.
还说我有那么一点迷信，偶尔天真。
That's not true.
那不是真的。
Well, the test isn't 100% accurate.
嗯，这个测试不是百分之百准确。
Is that all it says?
就这些吗？
No.
不。
It also says that I'm open minded with great ambition, but that I can also be reckless
还说我有开放的心态、雄心勃勃，但也可能鲁莽
and clumsy.
和笨手笨脚。
This is stupid.
这太蠢了。
Okay.
好吧。
Anyone else want to read theirs?
还有其他人想读自己的吗？
I'll go.
我来。
It says that I'm an extroverted, well balanced person.
上面说我是一个外向、平衡的人。
It says I am generous, outspoken and very diligent.
说我慷慨、直言不讳、非常勤奋。
This is so true.
这太准了。
It also says that I am a magnanimous, eloquent and daring.
还说我宽宏大量、口才好、勇敢。
This is totally me.
这完全就是我。
Whatever.
随便吧。
These tests are baloney.
这些测试都是胡扯。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So we're going to divide this up into language takeaway parts one and two.
我们会把这部分分成语言要点第一和第二部分。
So let's start with five key words now on language takeaway.
现在先从语言要点的五个关键词开始。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
The first adjective that came up was adventurous and outgoing.
第一个出现的形容词是爱冒险和外向。
Outgoing, that's a good one.
外向，这个词不错。
Outgoing is a great one.
外向是个好词。
So think of the word out.
想想“out”这个词。
That means moving out, going out.
意思是向外、出去。
Outgoing means someone is very comfortable talking to strangers or talking to people
外向指的是一个人很擅长和陌生人或不熟悉的人交谈。
that they don't know very well.
For example, my brother is very outgoing.
比如，我哥哥非常外向。
He loves meeting new people.
他喜欢认识新朋友。
He loves starting conversations with strangers.
他喜欢和陌生人搭话。
So the opposite would be shy.
所以反义词是害羞。
That's the opposite.
那就是反义词。
Okay, so outgoing.
好的，所以是外向。
And then it also described this person as being a little superstitious.
然后它还描述这个人有点迷信。
Okay, superstitious is very interesting because it's hard to describe since everyone's superstitions
好的，迷信这个词很有意思，因为很难描述，每个人的迷信都不一样。
are different.
In many cultures, there are different superstitions.
在很多文化中，有不同的迷信。
So for example, in America, we say that walking under a ladder is bad luck.
比如，在美国，我们说从梯子下走过会带来坏运气。
Or opening an umbrella inside is bad luck.
或者在室内打开雨伞会带来坏运气。
So if you believe that your actions will bring you bad luck, you're probably superstitious.
所以如果你相信你的行为会带来坏运气，那你可能就迷信。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So if you are superstitious, you believe in superstitions.
所以如果你迷信，你就相信迷信。
That's right.
没错。
So Marco, are you superstitious?
那么Marco，你迷信吗？
Do you think that black cats bring bad luck?
你觉得黑猫会带来坏运气吗？
No, not at all.
不，一点也不。
No.
不。
That's very interesting.
那很有意思。
All right.
好的。
And this is also an interesting word, a way to describe people who are very believing,
这也是一个有趣的词，用来描述非常轻信的人，
a person that is naive.
天真的人。
Okay, you said this already.
好的，你刚才说过了。
Naive means that someone generally believes most things that you tell them.
天真指的是一个人通常相信你告诉他的大部分事情。
So if I told you, Marco, hey, did you know that it's supposed to rain frogs tomorrow?
所以如果我告诉你，Marco，嘿，你知道吗，明天要下青蛙雨？
No way.
不会吧。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, really.
是的，真的。
If Marco believes me, he's naive.
如果马可相信我，那他就太天真了。
That means that probably it's not going to rain frogs tomorrow, but he believes everything
这意味着明天可能不会下青蛙雨，但他相信我说的
I say.
每一句话。
So he's a little bit naive or inexperienced.
所以他有点天真或缺乏经验。
So naive is not really a bad way of describing a person, is it?
所以“天真”并不是一个描述人的坏词，对吧？
No, but it can be.
不，但它可以是。
So you want to be careful.
所以你要小心。
Some people, if you say that they're being naive, it's offensive.
有些人，如果你说他们天真，那会冒犯到他们。
So you have to be careful when you say this.
所以你说这个词时要小心。
Okay.
好的。
Moving on, we also had an interesting adjective that described another person, and it was
继续，我们还有一个有趣的形容词，用来描述另一个人，那就是
to be reckless.
鲁莽。
I can also be reckless.
我也可以很鲁莽。
Reckless.
鲁莽。
Okay.
好的。
So someone who is reckless often does things without thinking, sometimes things that are
所以一个鲁莽的人经常做事不经思考，有时会做
dangerous.
危险的事。
For example, Marco, I think that driving a car without wearing your seatbelt is very
例如，马可，我觉得开车不系安全带是非常
reckless.
鲁莽的。
Okay.
好的。
That means that you're not thinking about safety.
这意味着你没有考虑安全。
Right.
对。
So a person that is reckless is a kind of a synonym of being a little bit dangerous to
所以一个鲁莽的人，某种程度上是那种待在一起有点
be around.
危险的人。
That's right.
没错。
So someone who does things without thinking about their consequences, their results.
所以就是做事不考虑后果、不考虑结果的人。
Okay.
好的。
And also along with reckless, the test said that this person was clumsy.
除了鲁莽，测试还说这个人很笨拙。
Oh, I love this word.
哦，我喜欢这个词。
There was a very famous commercial when I was growing up in America on the television.
我小时候在美国长大时，电视上有一个很有名的广告。
It was all about young students at high school who are clumsy, and so they should buy this
讲的是高中里笨拙的学生，所以他们应该买这种
special folder for their schoolwork to help them because they're so clumsy.
特殊的文件夹来帮助学习，因为他们太笨拙了。
And they're dropping their papers and their books.
他们总是掉纸和书。
Exactly.
没错。
So someone who is clumsy often falls down or hits their head or trips or drops their
所以一个笨拙的人经常摔倒、撞到头、绊倒或掉
things.
东西。
If I drop something on the floor and break it, my mother might say, you're so clumsy.
如果我把东西掉在地上摔碎了，我妈妈可能会说，你真笨拙。
Clumsy fingers.
笨手笨脚。
You should be more careful.
你应该更小心点。
Yeah.
是啊。
So clumsy, is this insulting if you say, oh, you're so clumsy?
所以“笨拙”这个词，如果你说“哦，你真笨拙”，这算冒犯吗？
No, it's not so bad.
不，没那么严重。
There are worse things to say.
还有更糟的话可以说。
But if someone often drops things, you can call them clumsy.
但如果有人经常掉东西，你可以说他们笨拙。
Or you can also say, you're such a butterfingers.
或者你也可以说，你真是个黄油手。
Butterfingers.
黄油手。
That means that your fingers are like butter.
意思是你的手指像黄油一样。
They're very slippery.
很滑。
You drop everything.
什么都拿不住。
Okay.
好的。
So clumsy and reckless, they are negative adjectives, right?
所以笨拙和鲁莽，都是负面形容词，对吧？
They're saying that you do things wrong.
它们是在说你做错了事。
So it's not really a good thing to be reckless or clumsy.
所以鲁莽或笨拙并不是好事。
No, it's not really a good thing.
不，确实不是好事。
These are not positive characteristics.
这些不是积极的性格特征。
Okay, good.
好的，明白了。
So we took a look at those five, which are very good about one of the people that took
所以我们看了这五个词，它们很好地描述了参加测试的一个人。
the test.
测试。
Let's move on now to more language and more adjectives on Language Takeaway part two.
现在让我们继续，在“语言摘录”第二部分中学习更多语言和形容词。
Language Takeaway.
语言摘录。
Alright, so in this part, we're going to take a look at positive attributes about a person,
好的，在这一部分，我们要看看一个人的积极特质，
right?
对吧？
They're all good things about someone.
都是关于一个人的好品质。
That's right.
没错。
And this first one is very good.
第一个词非常好。
Extroverted, extroverted.
外向的，外向的。
A person that's extroverted.
一个外向的人。
So a synonym of this word is outgoing.
所以这个词的同义词是“开朗的”。
Okay, so it's pretty much the same thing.
好的，所以基本上是一回事。
That's right, because extra means going out, out.
没错，因为“extra”意思是向外、出去。
So in this case, someone who is extroverted often meets new people, goes out and does
所以在这种情况下，一个外向的人经常结识新朋友，出去做
social things, goes to the movies, goes out with friends, meets strangers, talks to strangers.
社交活动，比如看电影、和朋友出去玩、见陌生人、和陌生人聊天。
Again, it's like being outgoing.
就像开朗一样。
Someone who's comfortable with new people.
一个和新人相处很自在的人。
And what about the opposite?
那反义词呢？
So we said that shy is the opposite of outgoing.
我们说害羞是开朗的反义词。
What would be the opposite for extroverted?
那外向的反义词是什么？
Extroverted's opposite is introverted.
外向的反义词是内向。
Intro means in, not out.
“Intro”意思是向内，不是向外。
So that means someone who's very shy, who is uncomfortable with new people.
所以那意味着一个非常害羞、和新人相处不自在的人。
Okay.
好的。
And well, apart from being extroverted, the test also said that this person is very diligent.
嗯，除了外向之外，测试还显示这个人非常勤奋。
Ooh, diligent is a great word.
哦，勤奋是个好词。
This is a word you want to hear from your teachers and your bosses.
这是你想从老师和老板那里听到的词。
Okay, if someone says, Marco, you're very diligent at work.
好的，如果有人对你说，马可，你在工作中非常勤奋。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
It means you're very careful.
意思是你非常细心。
You always do things very thoroughly.
你总是把事情做得非常彻底。
And also quickly, right?
而且还要快，对吧？
When you tell them to do something, they do it immediately.
当你让他们做某事时，他们会立刻去做。
That's right.
没错。
So a diligent worker always does a good job and does it in a timely manner.
所以一个勤奋的工人总是把工作做好，并且及时完成。
Okay.
好的。
And moving on to our third adjective.
接下来是我们的第三个形容词。
This one is kind of strange.
这个有点奇怪。
It kind of sounds like monogamy, but it's magnanimous.
听起来有点像“一夫一妻制”，但它是“宽宏大量的”。
Magnanimous.
宽宏大量的。
All right.
好的。
Magnanimous.
宽宏大量的。
This is a great word.
这是个好词。
We hear this a lot in the newspaper or on TV about usually famous people.
我们经常在报纸或电视上听到这个词，通常用来形容名人。
He did something very magnanimous or it was a magnanimous gesture.
他做了一件非常宽宏大量的事，或者那是一个宽宏大量的姿态。
This describes a person who does things for the benefit of other people.
这个词描述的是一个为他人利益着想的人。
Who is thinking about the well-being and the health and the lives of others.
一个关心他人福祉、健康和生活的人。
So it would be a person that likes to share or a person that's not selfish.
所以，这是一个乐于分享的人，或者是一个不自私的人。
Right.
没错。
So if you donate half of your salary this month to victims of an earthquake, I would
所以，如果你这个月把一半的工资捐给地震灾民，我会
say, Marco, that's so magnanimous of you.
说，Marco，你真是太宽宏大量了。
You're so magnanimous.
你太宽宏大量了。
Okay.
好的。
Awesome.
太棒了。
And apart from being magnanimous, if a person is eloquent, I guess that's also a positive
除了宽宏大量之外，如果一个人能言善辩，我想那也是一个积极的
attribute.
特质。
Yeah.
是的。
This is another really good one.
这也是一个非常好的词。
Someone who is eloquent is a very good speaker.
能言善辩的人是一个很会说话的人。
This means that when they talk, they sound very, very good.
这意味着他们说话时，听起来非常非常好。
Someone who's eloquent uses big words, but is also very good at making other people listen.
能言善辩的人会用大词，但也非常擅长让别人倾听。
So it's usually about speaking.
所以这通常与说话有关。
So you would say he's an eloquent speaker.
所以你可以说他是一个能言善辩的演讲者。
That's right.
没错。
So someone who is eloquent is fun or good or interesting to listen to.
所以，一个口才好的人，听起来有趣、好听或引人入胜。
And our last description for personalities and the way people are is a person that's
我们最后一个描述性格和为人方式的词是
daring.
大胆的。
Well, this can be a good thing or a bad thing.
嗯，这可能是好事也可能是坏事。
It depends on who you're talking about.
这取决于你在说谁。
Because sometimes daring people are also reckless and this can be dangerous.
因为有时候大胆的人也很鲁莽，这可能很危险。
But sometimes someone who is daring can be doing good things.
但有时候大胆的人也能做好事。
Like a daring business person might take risks that other people don't take.
比如一个大胆的商人可能会冒别人不敢冒的风险。
Okay.
好的。
So a person that's daring dares to take risks, right?
所以，一个大胆的人敢于冒险，对吧？
You are very daring.
你非常大胆。
You Marco are daring because recently you jumped out of an airplane.
你，Marco，很大胆，因为你最近从飞机上跳了下来。
Yeah.
是啊。
You did some skydiving.
你跳了伞。
So that would be considered daring.
所以那就算是大胆。
That's very daring.
那非常大胆。
I'm not daring like that because I would never jump out of an airplane.
我可没那么大胆，因为我绝不会从飞机上跳下来。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So we took a look at basically 10 key words here.
所以我们基本上看了10个关键词。
A lot of adjectives, but they're a great way to describe yourself.
很多形容词，但它们是描述自己的好方法。
Maybe if you're at a job interview, sometimes a typical question is, how would you describe
也许在求职面试时，一个常见的问题是：你如何描述自己？
yourself using three adjectives?
用三个形容词来形容你自己？
I'm extroverted, I'm diligent, and I'm open-minded.
我性格外向，勤奋努力，而且思想开放。
Yeah.
是的。
That's awesome.
太棒了。
See?
看到了吧？
You sound really professional when you say things like this.
你这样说的时候听起来真的很专业。
Give me the job.
把这份工作给我。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
So and even if you took a look at some of the negative adjectives that we used, it's
所以，即使你看了我们用过的一些负面形容词，也是这样的。
also a typical job interview question is like, what are your biggest faults?
还有一个典型的面试问题是，你最大的缺点是什么？
So you can say, well, maybe I am superstitious and naive.
所以你可以说，嗯，也许我既迷信又天真。
You wouldn't want to say that in a job interview.
你在面试时肯定不会这么说。
But I mean, I don't know, maybe.
但我是说，我也不确定，也许吧。
Because you have to say something, right?
因为你总得说点什么，对吧？
You do.
你确实有。
But I would say, sometimes I'm a bit too daring or sometimes I take things personally.
但我觉得吧，有时候我有点太大胆了，或者有时候太容易把事往心里去。
So we can talk about that another time.
那我们改天再聊这个。
But I think for now, it'd be good if we listened to today's dialogue one more time and really
不过我觉得现在最好再听一遍今天的对话，真正
got a good sense of how to use these words.
掌握这些词的用法。
Okay, class, settle down.
好了，同学们，安静下来。
I have the results of your individual personality tests.
我拿到了你们个人性格测试的结果。
I am going to hand them out.
我会把它们发下去。
And if you'd like, you can read them out loud to the rest of the class.
如果你们愿意，可以大声读给全班同学听。
I'll read mine.
我来读我的。
Okay, go ahead.
好的，请吧。
It says here that I am adventurous, outgoing, and easygoing.
上面说我爱冒险、外向、随和。
It says that I'm a little superstitious and occasionally naive.
还说我有点迷信，偶尔天真。
That's not true.
那不是真的。
Well, the test isn't 100% accurate.
嗯，这个测试不是百分之百准确。
Is that all it says?
就这些吗？
No.
不。
It also says that I'm open-minded with great ambition, but that I can also be reckless
还说我有开阔的胸怀和远大的抱负，但有时也鲁莽
and clumsy.
和笨拙。
This is stupid.
这太蠢了。
Okay, anyone else want to read theirs?
好了，还有谁想读自己的？
I'll go.
我来。
It says that I'm an extroverted, well-balanced person.
上面说我是一个外向、平衡的人。
It says I am generous, outspoken, and very diligent.
说我慷慨、直言不讳、非常勤奋。
This is so true.
这太准了。
It also says that I am a magnanimous, eloquent, and daring.
还说我宽宏大量、口才好、勇敢。
This is totally me.
这完全就是我。
Whatever.
随便吧。
These tests are baloney.
这些测试都是胡扯。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now going into descriptions.
现在进入描述部分。
What are three adjectives that you would use to describe someone that you hate the most?
你会用哪三个形容词来描述你最讨厌的人？
So going back to describing people, how would you describe one of the main things that really
回到描述人的话题，你会怎么描述别人身上最让你
irritate you about someone?
恼火的一个主要特点？
Maybe if they are clumsy, it really bothers you that people are clumsy or reckless maybe.
比如，如果某人笨手笨脚，你可能很烦；或者鲁莽。
I see what you're saying.
我明白你的意思。
Well, I really like extroverted, hardworking people, but in English we have a word to describe
嗯，我真的很喜欢外向、勤奋的人，但在英语里，我们有一个词来形容
someone who is too extroverted, too hardworking.
过于外向、过于勤奋的人。
We call this person a type A personality.
我们称这种人为A型人格。
Type A. Type A.
A型。A型。
The letter A. And this means someone who works very, very hard, who is very, very serious,
字母A。这指的是工作非常非常努力、非常非常认真，
but who's always anxious, always needs to get things done.
但总是焦虑、总想完成任务的人。
And so these people can be very hard to work with because they're controlling and they're
所以这种人很难共事，因为他们控制欲强，
never calm.
从不放松。
So they're not easygoing.
所以他们不随和。
No, they're not easygoing.
对，他们不随和。
They always want to do what they want to do.
他们总想按自己的方式做事。
They're usually not very good listeners.
他们通常不太善于倾听。
And so this type A personality is something that I would say I'm not a big fan of at work
所以这种A型人格，我得说在工作时我不太喜欢，
or even when we're going out because with friends, it's hard to be around someone who
甚至出去玩时也是，因为跟朋友在一起，很难跟一个
always has to control you.
总想控制你的人相处。
This is very interesting.
这很有意思。
And I'm sure our listeners have a lot of different ways to describe things that irritate them,
我相信我们的听众有很多不同的方式描述让他们恼火的事情，
maybe about people or maybe attributes that they really admire about someone.
可能是关于人的，也可能是他们真正欣赏的某些特质。
That's right.
没错。
And I want to give everybody a little bit of homework today.
我想给大家布置一点今天的作业。
Go home or if you're at home, look up a word in the dictionary that describes yourself.
回家后，或者如果你在家，查一个字典里的词来描述你自己。
Yeah.
嗯。
An adjective to describe yourself.
一个描述你自己的形容词。
I think this is a really good homework assignment because you'll be improving your vocabulary
我觉得这是个很好的作业，因为你能提高词汇量，
and then put it on our website, EnglishPod.com.
然后把它发到我们的网站EnglishPod.com上。
Let us know more about you.
让我们多了解你。
Okay.
好的。
We'll see everyone there.
我们到时候见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Copyright © 2020 The Ellen DeGeneres, No Parnish
版权 © 2020 艾伦·德杰尼勒斯，无帕尼什